Hey everybody, welcome to
content video going over
section 8.10, characters
and character testing.
So the idea behind this chapter
is that we want to test to
see if something is truly
alphanumeric or if it contains
things that are alphabetic or
integers but all string values,
right? So there's a couple
of built-in Python functions
that we check to see if something
is alphanumeric so there's one
called is digit that will look
to see if every character in
the string is a digit so like
negative 27 for example not everything
is a digit because the negative
sign makes it not a digit
but if you take that off then
it returns true there's also is
alnum which looks to see if
everything is only digits and letters
So, for example, A9876
is alphanumeric, but this
123 Main Street is not
because it has spaces.
And there's a whole other list of
methods like this. So, is alpha, which
is only alphabetic characters, is
decimal, is identifier, is lower,
is numeric, is space, is tidal, and
is upper, which looks like ISupper.
Yeah, I don't know.
So, anyways, let's do
an example together.
So this is string character test.
So let's say we've got
a string negative 1, 2,
3, 4, 5. So if we print
it out, string is digit,
we would expect to see false because,
oh, sorry. This is not a string.
now it's a string
yeah we would expect to see false
because the string that we included
is um it's got that negative
sign in there whereas if we take
that off just like the example in
the textbook we see that that is true
so let's also do the alphanumeric
one let's take an address like
that one it gave us address
equals one two three
North Main Street, Logan,
Utah.
That might be somewhere.
I don't know, actually.
So then we print address.isAlnum,
and we would expect to see false
because we've got lots of spaces
in there. So what can we do to make
this all alphanumeric? Well, we
could do some string replacing so we
could say address equals address
dot replace and we could replace the
spaces with nothing we could replace
the periods with nothing what
else we got a comma we could replace
the comma with nothing and then
let's print out what that looks
like and then prints out address dot
is on them see what that gives us
so once we take out all the white
space notice we're not really like
stripping the white space we're
actually just replacing the white
space and the punctuation with
nothings oh oh I messed up again I
forgot to put parentheses on the end.
Then we see that our address is now
alphanumeric. So that's everything for
this content video.
Thank you for watching.